# **MEHRAN SADEGHI**

#### Front-end Engineer

Esfahan, Iran | +989162943105 | b.mehran.sadeghi@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/mehran-sadeghi

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Karnameh, Front-end Engineer, August 2022 - Present

Karnameh is one of the services of Divar with the aim of creating a better user experience in buying and selling cars and as a complementary service of Divar in the field of cars. This service intends to become a reliable assistant for Iranians in buying and selling cars and create a superior experience in buying and selling cars for you with services such as on-site car expertise and customized car sales.

#### SnappCarFix, Front-end Engineer, October 2021 - August 2022 (11 months)

- lead of front-end developers because of advocating best development practices and writing high-performance, reusable code in 3 Web Applications.
- Refactoring more than 80% of codes of all 3 projects with upgraded UI/UX and optimized theme in order to responsive web design concepts.
- Design a clean architecture for CSS based and decrease the unused CSS down to 70% with tools like styled-component, CSS-module, and bootstrap.
- Getting fluency in Map tools like mapbox-ql and implementing them in projects.
- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.

## Viramadar, Front-end Engineer, August 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 3 months)

- Responsible for implementing high-level graphical components with the combination of SVG and CSS in 3 projects
- Followed SDLC best practices within Agile Methodologies
- Increase SEO of websites to 100% score in google lighthouse
- Implementing my own npm package for React.js and using it in 2 projects of the company
- Design architecture of SSR and CSR projects and adapt the team to it
- More than 50% increase in the speed of SRR projects with tools like lazy loading
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility
- Responsible to manage repositories of 5 projects in git

## Jambod, Android Intern, July 2019 - October 2019 (4 months)

- Recycling management application with an uber like functionality.
- Developed real-time location tracking of drivers
- Decreased latency by using a push-based system instead of an older pull based one

**SKILLS** 

React.js, Next.js, Redux, SASS, Styled-component, TypeScript, TDD, React Hooks, SSR, Regex, Responsive

web design, Routing, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

**EDUCATION** 

Lorestan University, Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

**ABOUT ME** 

I'm a Web Developer, currently working as Front-end Developer at SnappCarFix, an online platform for Car parts

and services, backed by Snapp (Uber clone). I have around 3 years of experience in software development. My

aim is to enhance user experience and create new values in addition to delivering a clean scalable code, by

being closely in touch with the end-users.

LANGUAGES

English: Intermediate

Persian: Native

**PROJECTS** 

Radar-ch: My npm package for React.js and Next.js Shows what it gives as a radar graph.

Npm link: npmjs.com/package/radar-ch

Demo: radar-ch.surge.sh

Polvar: Polvar is an online shop selling mobile phones and contains a Comparison system (versus clone).

Link: polvar.com

Maxeo: Maxeo is a powerful SEO analyzer for websites (google light house clone) with various more features.

Link: maxeo.io

AirGo: AirGo Heating and Air Conditioning is Toronto's most trusted provider of heating and air conditioning

services.

Link: air-go.ca

SnappCarfix, Carfillo, HiGaraj: These websites all are online shops for selling car parts and Services to drivers

Links: snappcarfix.com, carfillo.com, higaraj.com

**Vima:** this is Viramadar's project that unfortunately fails. All the graphical designs of this website are implemented with me and I didn't use any library package for all graphical elements.

Link: vima.surge.sh